Yannelly Sanchez

22856 Willard Ave., Lake Forest, CA 92630

949-680-9711 | yannelly.sanchez389@gmail.com | ysanchez.github.io | www.linkedin.com/in/yannelly-sanchez-a923a237

Profile

An experienced Analyst with a M.A. in Forensic Psychology. My skills range from intensive Python and real world experience in Real Estate. In the last couple years, I have also gained comparable experience in Analytics by working at a financial company that specializes in global money wires transfers. Independently, I have broadened my knowledge and skills with data science projects such as Advanced Regression.

Technical Skills

Natural Language Processing: Tweepy, Twython, textblob, NLTK

Machine Learning: classification, regression, clustering, feature engineering

Statistical Methods: time series, regression models

Software and Programming Languages: Python (scikit-learn, numpy, scipy, pandas), Microsoft

Excel, R, Spark

Technical Experience- Projects

Housing Pricing (2017). Advanced regression through Kaggle.com. It determines the price of a house in lowa using Gradient Boosting.

Natural Language Processing (2017). A Twitter project using Search API in one notebook and API steaming in another. Used textblob to classify each tweet as "positive", "negative", or "neutral".

Loan Default (2017). Classification model which predicted loan defaults.

Serial Killer Prediction (2017). An FBI data set on Kaggle.com with 40 years of homicide data. Using Seaborn and Matplotlib to determine who was a serial killer and who was not.

Employment

Pricing Analyst: Ria Financial

2015 - Present

Analyze data in geographical areas to determine what group agents should be placed, which makes each agent competitive and successful. Investigative Analysis to determine current market trends for emerging markets. Used Census Bureau data to create an ArcGIS map based on demographics of the nation, which the Sales team now uses for prospecting. Clean data for the Pricing team and other departments using Python.

Investigator: Horsemen Investigations

2014 - 2015

Investigated Workers Compensations claims by completing one on one interviews with employees and managers that worked directly the claimant. Wrote detailed reports based on finding and material provided by the employer.

Service Coordinator: Regional Center of Orange County

2009 - 2014

Managed a caseload of 100+ clients with developmental disabilities. Worked collaboratively with other departments and vendors to create a program that best met the needs to of the clients. An advocate for the clients and parents during Individualized Education Program meetings, Annual Reviews, and Planning Team Meetings.

Education

Dev Masters

Winter 2017 - Summer 2017

Certificate - Python for Data Science

Argosy University

Spring 2009 - Winter 2010

Master of Arts in Forensic Psychology

University of California, Irvine 2009

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology

Fall 2006 - Spring